adea.org 2018-07-11

# ADEA Privacy Policy

##  ADEA Privacy Policy

**Last updated:** June 2018

The American Dental Education Association (ADEA) respects your privacy and we have developed the following policy to demonstrate our commitment to you. This privacy policy applies to all personal information we collect, including personal information collected via the ADEA website located at www.adea.org (the Site), ADEA programs and services, other websites that link to this policy (also referred to as the Site), web-based applications and surveys. Please note that some other ADEA websites may have unique privacy policies in which case they will link to a different ADEA privacy policy. The purpose of the privacy policy is to describe 1) the types of information collected, 2) how that information is used, and 3) the choices users have about the collection and use of this information.

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please send us an email at [privacy@adea.org](mailto:privacy@adea.org) or write us at ADEA, Attn: Web Services, 655 K Street, NW, Suite 800, Washington, DC 20001.

## Information we collect

### **_Personal Information_**

As part of ADEA’s efforts to better serve our members, we may collect certain information that identifies, or can be used to identify you specifically (“personal information”) to provide various product features. For example, we collect personal information in connection with ADEA GoDental®, ADEA weTeach®, ADEA AADSAS®, ADEA CAAPID®, ADEA PASS®, ADEA DHCAS®, _ADEA Official Guide to Dental Schools_ , _ADEA Directory of Institutional Members and Association Officers_ (ADEA DIM), _Journal of Dental Education_ ( _JDE_ ), dentalschoolexplorer.adea.org, the ADEA Advocacy website, as well as conference registrations, program or poster submissions, and any conference evaluations. This personal information is provided voluntarily by you when you participate in a program or survey or register for or purchase a product or service available through ADEA, or when you otherwise communicate with us. This information may include, but is not limited to, the following:

  * **Contact information** , such as name, postal address, phone number, email address, place of business, and professional titles. We collect this information, for example, when you subscribe to a newsletter or register for a conference.
  * **Background information** , such as demographics, employment, memberships, affiliations, special interests, and education. 
  * **Emergency and health information** , such as emergency contacts, dietary and health conditions. We collect such information as part of conference registrations to ensure compliance with the Americans with Disability Act.
  * **Purchase data** , such as payment information required for purchases.
  * **Application data** , such as institution name, contact information as listed above, usernames, DENTPIN, etc. as required to complete an online dental education or membership application.
  * **Political advocacy data** , such as your congressional district and advocacy expertise.
  * **User-generated content** , such as postings to online bulletin boards and online chat functions.
  * **Survey data,** such as that collected through our annual faculty survey, website, annual session and ADEA Centralized Application Services (to name a few).
  * **Donor data,** such as pledge and donor recognition information to support the ADEAGies Foundation, etc.

### **_Credit Card Information_**

Once your credit card information, including the CVV number, has been passed to the credit card processing company for verification, we do not retain the full credit card number or CVV number. Only partial information is retained by ADEA for future identification of the transaction. We employ reasonable security measures to protect your credit card information.

### **_Automatically Collected Information Including Cookies_**

In addition, our web servers automatically collect and log web usage data from you when you visit the Site. This information includes your IP address, referring sites, pages viewed, and length of visit, and informs us about how visitors use and navigate the Site. We and third parties may also collect cookie-based information across websites for purposes of website analytics and targeted advertising. 

Like most websites, we and third parties use cookies to help users more efficiently use our website. A cookie is a string of information that is sent by a website and stored by a user’s browser. We use cookies to continually enhance your experience and may use them to store your preferences and to customize content specific to your needs. We also use cookies to help us compile data about site traffic and site interaction so we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. When you use our website, we and third parties may collect information about you across the websites you visit. If you do not want your browser to accept cookies, you can modify the cookie option in your browser’s settings. However, some website features or services may not function properly or be accessible without cookies.

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our Site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy](http://google.com/privacy_ads.html).

We have implemented the following:

  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting.
  * Demographics and Interests Reporting.
  * Integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data.

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google, use cookies such as the Google Analytics cookies and DoubleClick cookie or other third-party identifiers to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website. 

### **_Opting out_**

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the [Google Ad Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) page. Alternatively, you can opt out of third party advertising cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#/) opt-out page and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page. To opt-out of Google Analytics, you may use the [Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). 

## How we use the information collected

We may combine the personal information you provide ADEA with other information that is available to us, including information submitted by users to ADEA offline and information collected from other third parties. Except as described below, ADEA does not rent or sell your personal information to unaffiliated third parties without your consent, but may use and share your information to, among other things:

  * Provide the product, information, or service requested.
  * Carry out an objective authorized by the user or otherwise disclosed to the user at the time the data are collected (e.g., we share applicant data with the dental school, dental hygiene, and/or advanced education programs designated by an applicant).
  * Improve the content, navigation, and efficiency of the Site.
  * Target, personalize, and develop our products and services to meet your individual interests and needs.
  * Communicate with you (1) through legislative alerts and newsletters, (2) to respond to your inquiries, (3) to disseminate surveys and survey results, and (4) to market ADEA's products and services and make you aware of other ADEA benefits.
  * Create email, Listserv, and other member lists to facilitate communication with and between our users.
  * Analyze information about our users and programs. 

We engage in these activities in furtherance of our contractual obligations to you or for precontractual measures, based on our legitimate interests in improving our processes and providing our services to you and others, or with your consent. 

## **How we share the information collected**

We may share your information:

  * With a recipient you have designated for the information. 
  * With representatives of ADEA Institutional Members (e.g., to inform them of members that have joined from their schools or programs). 
  * With third-party suppliers and service providers to provide services on behalf of ADEA and to fulfill the products and services offered through our Site. We may make personal information available to them to the extent necessary for them to provide services (e.g., to process a credit card payment, ship you a product). These third-party service providers include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users. We contractually require these third parties to keep this information confidential.
  * With law enforcement, regulators, or other entities as required by valid legal processes, such as a search warrant, subpoena, or court order; or if we find that a user’s actions violate our policies; or to protect our rights and property.

In addition, we may use and share with others statistics or other aggregated or de-identified (not personally identifiable) information derived from information about you. This type of information includes, but is not limited to, information that we have collected based on web usage data, surveys, or statistical information that we have compiled about our users. 

We may also disclose your personal information in connection with any merger or consolidation with, or sale of assets to a third party.

### **_Choice_**

If you would prefer not to receive marketing or other promotional communications from ADEA, please notify us of your preferences. Many of our products and services allow you to make these choices at the time you submit personal information and allow you to access your profile and change your preferences online. You may also change your preferences regarding the types of communications you receive from ADEA by emailing us at [membership@adea.org](mailto:membership@adea.org) or, for ADEA members, logging into the ADEA site and clicking on the MyADEA link at the top to update your communications preferences. 

### **_Security_**

Messages that you send to us by email may not be secure. We recommend that you do not send any confidential information to us by email. If you choose to send confidential information to us via email, you accept the risk that a third party may intercept this information.

### **Children**

The Site is not directed toward children under 13 years of age, nor do we knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not submit personal information to us. 

### **_Third-party Links_**

Our websites may contain links to other sites. Links do not imply endorsement by ADEA. Please be aware that these other sites are not subject to the ADEA privacy policy and we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We recommend that you review the privacy policies of those sites when you visit them. Nonetheless, we seek to provide helpful links and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## Reviewing and correcting your information

For several of our products and services (including online applications and Communities of Interest), you can access and update your personal information directly by logging into your online ADEA account, by calling us at 202-289-7201 or by sending an email to [membership@adea.org](mailto:membership@adea.org). We try to keep information about you accurate and current, but if you find errors or inaccuracies in your information, please let us know. To protect your privacy and security, we may take reasonable steps to verify your identity before we disclose or make any corrections to this information. In certain jurisdictions, like if you are an individual in the European Economic Area, you have the right, subject to certain exceptions, to make additional requests, such as the right to request your information be deleted, the right to restrict processing, and the right to portability. You can make these requests at the contact information provided above.

### **_Your California Privacy Rights_**

If you reside in California and have provided your personal information to us, you may request information once per calendar year about our disclosures of certain categories of your personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us in writing at the following - Attn: Membership, ADEA, 655 K Street, NW, Suite 800, Washington, DC 20001 or by email at [membership@adea.org](mailto:membership@adea.org). 

### **_International Data Transfer_**

We are based in the United States and have members in the United States and Canada. Your personal information will be received and may otherwise be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States or another country that may not provide the same level of protection for personal information as the laws of your home country, and may be available to the government of the United States or such other country under a lawful request or order made in those countries.

## Changes to this privacy policy

We will occasionally update this privacy policy. When we do, we will also revise the “last updated” date at the top of the privacy policy. For material changes, we will take reasonable steps to notify you, such as by sending an email or by placing a prominent notice on our main website, [adea.org](mailto:http://www.adea.org/). Please check the Site from time to time for the most current version of our privacy policy. Your continued use of the Site constitutes your acceptance of the changes.

### **_Questions_**

Where applicable, ADEA is considered the controller of the personal information we collect. You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority concerning our processing of your personal data. However, it is our preference to first resolve any concerns you have with you directly. If you have questions, comments, requests, or concerns related to this privacy policy, please contact ADEA at [privacy@adea.org](mailto:privacy@adea.org)or at the contact information below.

ADEA  
Attn: Web Services  
655 K Street, NW, Suite 800  
Washington, DC 20001  
202-289-7201

© 2018 American Dental Education Association. All Rights Reserved.
